dlife.com 2019-10-07

# Privacy Policy | dLife

## Privacy Policy

## I. Objective and Scope

LifeMed Media, Inc. (“we”, “us”, “dLife.com”) values the trust placed in us by data subject (“you”, “your”, “user”, “subscriber”) and therefore, we follow the highest standards of privacy guidelines to protect the information shared by you with us.

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) governs the use of Personal Information shared (as defined below) with or collected by dLife.com from the users or subscribers.

This privacy policy describes the usage of information provided or collected on the sites and applications where this privacy policy is posted. We follow this privacy policy in accordance with applicable law in the places where we operate. In some cases, we may provide additional data privacy notices specific to certain services or regions. Those terms are to be read in combination with this policy.

Please keep in mind that when you provide information to us on a third-party site or platform (for example, via our applications like social media login the information we collect is through those third-party sites linked with our applications is covered by this privacy policy, and the information the third-party site or platform collects is subject to the third-party site or platform’s privacy practices. Privacy choices you have made on the third-party site or platform will not apply to our use of the information we have collected directly through our applications. Please also keep in observance that our sites and applications may contain links to other sites not owned or controlled by us and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our sites or applications and to read the privacy policies of other sites that may collect your personal information.

All capitalized terms that have not been specifically defined herein shall have the same meaning as provided under the Terms of Use.

This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction and together with the Terms of Use applicable to dLife.com you are using.

## II. User Consent

By using dLife.com (for example, when you register for an account, purchase a service, enter a contest or promotions, communicate with us, on our sites or applications), you agree to provide consent to our collection, use and sharing of your personal information as described in this policy. In some cases, particularly if you reside in a country governed by a data protection regulation, we may ask you to provide explicit consent to access our services before proceeding for further operations.

## III. Collection and Use of Personal Information

‘Personal Information’ or ‘PII’ is defined as any information that identifies (whether directly or indirectly) to a particular individual or natural person, such as the individual’s name, postal address, email address, and mobile number indicating to that particular person or is identifiable. When anonymous information is directly or indirectly associated with personal information, the resulting information also is treated as personal information.

## IV. Information you provide to us

We may ask for and collect the following personal information about you when you use dLife.com’s services and without this information we may not be able to provide you with all the requested services;

  * First and Last Name
  * Email id
  * Mobile No.
  * City & State

## V. Information we collect automatically

We collect information about you and your use of our service, your interactions with us and our advertising, as well as information regarding your computer or other device used to access our service. The information includes:

  * Your interactions with our email, customer care and messaging platform.
  * Geo-location information through IP addresses,
  * Information collected via the use of cookies and other technologies; (You can read more about how we use cookies in our [Cookie Policy](http://www.dlife.com/cookie-policy/)).

## VI. Special Category of Information

Certain types of personal information are more sensitive than others. This includes information about health, disability, race, ethnicity, criminal offences (or alleged offences), political opinions, biometric information or religion. It is voluntary for you to disclose this information, but where we collect and receive these types of information about you, we have identified the type of special information, how we will use it and why we will use it.

Information you provide to us;

  * Diabetes Type 1 or Type 2
  * Healthcare professional or a Caregiver

## VII. Inferred Information through usage and log data

We may track certain information about you based upon your behaviour on dLife.com We use this information for conducting internal research on our users’ demographics, devices, interests, and behaviour to better understand, protect and serve our users. This information is compiled and analysed on an aggregated basis. This information may include the platform that you just visited (whether this platform is on dLife.com or not), which platform you next visit, your computer browser information.

We may also collect Your Information to track user behaviour and preferences for internal analytics and research. We may also use your information:

  * To evaluate Your interest for various genres of content, services, offers;
  * To perform analytics and conduct customer research, to determine your interest, for identifying Content that generate sales and to analyse traffic patterns.

If you choose to post messages on social media accounts, message boards, chat rooms or other message areas or leave feedback, we will collect that information you provide to us. We retain this information as necessary to resolve disputes, provide customer support and troubleshoot problems as permitted by law.

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on dLife.com, we may collect and store such information.

We identify and use your IP address to help diagnose any problems with our server, and to administer dLife.com. Your IP address is also used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information to customize your experience on dLife.com.

We will occasionally ask you to complete optional online surveys. These surveys may ask you for contact information and demographic information (like zip code, age, etc.). We use this data to tailor your experience on dLife.com, providing you with content that we think you might be interested in and to display content according to your preferences.

## VIII. Purposes and Lawfulness of processing

We will only collect and process personal data about you where we have lawful basis. Lawful basis on which we would process our personal information includes obtaining explicit consent from you for processing your personal information or processing for “legitimate interests” where processing is necessary by us to provide you with customer support (For e.g. providing feedback through our website).

We use information to provide, analyse, administer, enhance and personalize our service and marketing efforts, to process your registration, and to communicate with you related to below mentioned points. For example, we use information to:

  * prevent, detect and investigate potentially prohibited or illegal activities, including fraud, and enforcing our terms (such as determining free trial eligibility);
  * communicate with you concerning our service (for example by email, push notifications text messaging, and online messaging channels), so that we can send you news about dLife.com, details about new features and content available on dLife.com, and special offers, promotional announcements, and consumer surveys, and to assist you with operational requests such as password reset requests.
  * notify you about changes in terms of service.
  * allow you to participate in interactive features offered through our Services.

We may use your information to provide you with personalised experience when you visit/use one of our sites/apps, and for insight and marketing purposes.

We provide personalisation by using data you submit to us in terms of cookies, IP addresses, web beacons or similar technologies in relation to the devices you use. By doing so, we can provide you with contents and/or advertising that we believe is more relevant to your interests. Please provide explicit consent for the same when we collect your data and/or adjust your user preferences in your account profile concerning your choices/preferences provided.

You can click on [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) to modify your choices with respect to capturing of cookies from your website.

## VIII. Disclosure to third parties

### General Disclosure

At times LifeMed Media, Inc. may make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with LifeMed Media, Inc. to provide service, or that help LifeMed Media, Inc. market to customers. For example, when you purchase and activate subscription, you authorize the LifeMed Media, Inc. to exchange the information you provide during the activation process to carry out a service. If you are approved for service, your account will be governed by dLife.com’s privacy policy. Personal information will only be shared by LifeMed Media, Inc. to provide or improve our service and marketing aspects; it will not be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes.

We do not share your personal information with Companies, organizations, or individuals outside of LifeMed Media, Inc. except in the following cases:

### Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit or use our website, mobile application or services. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number or other personally identifiable information) about your visits or use to particular website, mobile application or services, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit or use our website, mobile application or services. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number or other personally identifiable information) about your visits or use to particular website, mobile application or services, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Services may include links to other websites or applications. Such websites or applications are governed by their respective privacy policies, and are beyond our reasonable control. Once you leave our server (you can recognize your location by checking the URL in location bar on your browser), any kind of information provided by you is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the applications/website(s) you are visiting. Their policy may differ from ours. If you can’t find the privacy policy of any of these applications/websites via a link from the application’s  
homepage, you should contact the application owner(s) directly for more information.

Presentation of information to our advertisers for helping them to understand our audience(s) and to know the value of advertising on our websites or applications, is usually in form of aggregated statistics on traffic to various pages/content within our websites or applications.

We do not provide any personally identifiable information to any third party websites / advertisers / ad-servers without obtaining your consent.

### Promotional Offers

We’ll share or disclose your personal information outside of LifeMed Media, Inc. when we have your consent. For example, providing E-mail related services such as marketing newsletters, promotions and offers.

### Business Transfers

We provide personal information to our affiliates and other trusted businesses or persons to process it for us, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. For example, we use service providers to help us with customer support.

### Legal

In the event of any requirement by court order, government or quasi-government agency to disclose Your Personal Information, We will disclose information as may be legally required. We may also disclose Your Personal Information if we, in the good faith believe that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process.

In the event LifeMed Media, Inc. is merged with or acquired by another company, we and our affiliates may share your personal information, wholly or in part, with another business entity.

## IX. Your Controls and Choices

We provide you the ability to exercise certain controls and choices regarding our collection, use and sharing of your personal information. In accordance with applicable law, your controls and choices may include:

### Managing Your Information

You can access and update some of your personal information through your account settings. If you have chosen to connect your dLife.com account to a third-party application, like Facebook, Google or Twitter, you can change your settings and remove permission for the app by changing your account settings. You are responsible for keeping your personal information up-to-date. dLife.com will send you periodic reminders via e-mail to maintain the accuracy of your personal information.

### Rectification of Inaccurate or Incomplete Information

You can ask us to correct inaccurate or incomplete personal information concerning you (this is the information which you cannot update yourself within your dLife.com account) by sending us an e-mail.

### Data Retention and Erasure

We retain your personal information as long as necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your information then you can request that we erase your personal information and close your dLife.com account. Please note that if your request for the erasure of your personal information;

  * We may retain some of your personal information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention and enhancing safety. For example, if we suspend a dLife.com account for fraud or safety reasons, we may retain certain information from that account to prevent that user from opening a new account in the future.
  * We may retain and use your personal information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations. For example, we may keep some of your information for tax, legal reporting and auditing obligations.
  * Because we maintain copies of the personal information to protect from accidental or malicious loss and destruction, residual copies of your personal information may not be removed from our backup systems for a limited period of time.

### Withdrawing Consent and Restriction of Processing

For withdrawing your consent at any time during the tenure of your services with us, you may choose to do so by sending us an e-mail. We shall review your request and may ask you to verify your identity. Post verification we will withdraw the consent for which request was made by you and stop any further processing of your personal information.

### Objection to Processing

Where your personal information is processed for direct marketing purposes, you may, at any time ask us to cease processing your data for these direct marketing purposes by sending an e-mail to us.

### Complaints

You can write to our data protection officer in case of any grievance or compliant. You have the right to complaint about the data processing activities carried out by LifeMed Media, Inc. before the competent data protection authorities.

Please be aware that if you do not allow us to collect personal information from you, we may not be able to deliver certain experiences, products, and services to you, and some of our services may not be able to take account of your interests and preferences. If collection of personal information is mandatory, we will make that clear at the point of collection so that you can make an informed decision whether to participate.  If you have questions about the specific personal information about you that we process or retain, and your rights regarding that personal information, please contact our customer support team.

## X. Children’s Privacy

dLife.com is not intentionally designed for or directed at persons less than 16 years of age. LifeMed Media, Inc. does not knowingly permit any person who is under 16 years of age to register with the services or to provide any other personally identifying information. If LifeMed Media, Inc. becomes aware that any personally identifiable information of persons less than 16 years of age has been collected on dLife.com without verified parental consent, then LifeMed Media, Inc. will take the appropriate steps to delete any such information and notify the parent.

However, we consider it the responsibility of parents to monitor their children’s use of our services. Nevertheless, it is our policy not to collect and process any personal information from children below 16 years of age or offer to send any promotional materials to persons in that category. LifeMed Media, Inc. does not seek or intend to seek or receive any personal information from children. Should a parent or guardian have reasons to believe that a minor has provided LifeMed Media, Inc. with personal information without their prior consent, please contact our customer support team to ensure that the personal information is removed from dLife.com.

## XI. Data transfer, storage & processing globally

We operate globally and may transfer your personal information to individual companies of LifeMed Media, Inc. affiliated companies or third parties in locations around the world for the purposes described in this privacy policy. Wherever your personal information is transferred, stored or processed by us, we will take reasonable steps to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. Additionally, when using or disclosing personal information transferred from the European Union, we use standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, adopt other means under European Union law for ensuring adequate safeguards.

## XII. Security and compliance with laws

We are continuously implementing and updating administrative, technical, and physical security measures to help protect your information against unauthorized access, loss, destruction, or alteration. Some of the safeguards we use to protect your information are firewalls and data encryption, and information access controls. If you know or have reason to believe that your dLife.com account credentials have been lost, stolen, altered, or otherwise compromised or in case of any actual or suspected unauthorized use of your account, please contact us by contacting our customer support team.

## XIII. Change in Policy

This Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to modify the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to ensure compliance with applicable laws (“Updated Terms”). The Updated Terms shall be effective immediately and shall supersede these the terms of this Privacy Policy. We will not be under an obligation to notify you of any changes to this privacy policy except if the changes made to the policy significantly affects your rights or as may be required by law. You shall be solely responsible for reviewing the Privacy Policy from time to time for any modifications. By continuing to use dLife.com after the updated Terms have been published, you affirm your agreement to the updated terms.

## XIV. Contact information

  1. Support  
If you require any information or clarification regarding the use of your personal information or this privacy policy or grievances with respect to use of your personal information, please email us at [gordon.f@atl.esselgroup.com](mailto:gordon.f@atl.esselgroup.com).
  2. Data Controller Officer  
The data controller for dLife.com is LifeMed Media, Inc. (200 Middlesex Turnpike, Iselin, NJ 08830)  
The data protection officer (DPO) appointed by LifeMed Media, Inc. is [Gordon Finlayson](mailto:gordon.f@atl.esselgroup.com).  
If you have any queries, complaints regarding the collecting, processing, transfer of personal data/information or regarding this policy please do contact our Data Protection Officer.
